<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title></title>
  <subtitle>FoxGibbon is your source for design news &amp; tutorials. Whether professional or enthusiast, it is a place to find information, source inspiration &amp; seek help.</subtitle>
  <link href="https://foxgibbon.com/feed/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href=""/>
  <updated>2023-11-03T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <id></id>
  <author>
    <name></name>
    <email></email>
  </author>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Cognitive Biases and User Experience</title>
    <link href="/posts/cognitive-biases-and-user-experience/"/>
    <updated>2023-11-03T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>/posts/cognitive-biases-and-user-experience/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Ever wondered why certain websites or products captivate us? The answer often lies in &lt;span&gt;cognitive biases&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cognitive bias are those mental shortcuts influencing our choices. For designers, comprehending these biases can be a game-changer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;1. Confirmation Bias&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People tend to favor information confirming their existing beliefs.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;+&lt;/strong&gt; Designers can tap into this by aligning design and content with users&#39; expectations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;-&lt;/strong&gt; To avoid manipulation, designers should maintain transparency, ensuring content and design don&#39;t selectively present information confirming existing biases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;2. Anchoring Bias&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We often rely heavily on the first information we encounter.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;+&lt;/strong&gt; For pricing, start with a higher option to make others seem more affordable. In different contexts, provide a clear starting point or instruction to guide choices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;-&lt;/strong&gt; Ensure anchors are informative, not coercive, to prevent users from feeling forced into undesirable choices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;3. Choice Supportive Bias&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People retroactively ascribe positive attributes to their past choices.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;+&lt;/strong&gt; After users make a choice, highlight the benefits of their chosen option, fostering a happier user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;-&lt;/strong&gt; Don&#39;t neglect alternative options; provide clear information about different choices to enhance trust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;4. Availability Heuristic&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People rely on readily available information when making decisions.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;+&lt;/strong&gt; Make crucial information easily available with clear and prominent design elements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;-&lt;/strong&gt; To avoid overwhelming users, focus on providing digestible essential data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;5. Social Proof Bias&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People conform to the actions or opinions of others.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;+&lt;/strong&gt; Incorporate social proof elements, like user reviews or endorsements, to positively influence users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;-&lt;/strong&gt; Beware of inauthentic social proof elements that can damage trust and credibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Further Reading:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a deeper dive into design psychology and cognitive biases, consider reading &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/en/book/show/28815&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Influence: The Psychology of Persuasion&amp;quot; by Robert Cialdini&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/11468377-thinking-fast-and-slow&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Thinking, Fast and Slow&amp;quot; by Daniel Kahneman&lt;/a&gt;. These books offer valuable insights into the subject.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Maximizing User Experience | Understanding Short-Term Memory in Website Interaction</title>
    <link href="/posts/maximizing-user-experience-understanding-short-term-memory-in-website-interaction/"/>
    <updated>2023-11-02T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>/posts/maximizing-user-experience-understanding-short-term-memory-in-website-interaction/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Despite the incredible advances of the past 100 years, &lt;span&gt;the human brain today is the same as the human brain 10,000 years ago&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to designing websites and ensuring an exceptional user experience, understanding the limitations of human cognition is crucial. One fundamental aspect of human memory, often overlooked in web design, is short-term memory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Capacity of Short-Term Memory&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psychologist George A. Miller proposed the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Magical_Number_Seven,_Plus_or_Minus_Two&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;7±2 rule&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt; in 1956, suggesting that people can effectively remember and process approximately 7 (plus or minus 2) chunks of information in their short-term memory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These chunks can be individual items or groups of related items. For example, a chunk of information might be a phone number, a word, or a color.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;If information isn&#39;t &lt;span&gt;rehearsed or moved into long-term memory&lt;/span&gt;, it can disappear from short-term memory in as little as &lt;span&gt;20 seconds&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When users interact with a website, they rely on their short-term memory to process and remember key information presented to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Implications for Web Design&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some considerations to enhance the user experience:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chunk Information:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Present information in manageable chunks. Avoid overwhelming users with too much content on a single page. Break it down into smaller sections to aid retention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prioritize Key Information:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ensure that the most critical information is presented prominently. Users are more likely to remember and act upon information placed in the spotlight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Minimize Distractions:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Avoid clutter and distractions on your website. A clean, organized layout helps users focus on the information they need to retain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use Visual Aids:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visuals, such as images, infographics, and icons, can help users process and remember information more effectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Implement Progressive Disclosure:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Present information progressively, revealing details in a logical order. This approach allows users to absorb and remember information step by step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Provide Cues and Reminders:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Include clear calls to action, buttons, or navigation aids to help users find their way back to important information.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Embrace the Amazing Gift of Limited Life</title>
    <link href="/posts/embrace-the-amazing-gift-of-limited-life/"/>
    <updated>2023-10-27T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>/posts/embrace-the-amazing-gift-of-limited-life/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;How many hours&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine for a moment that you can see how many hours you have left in your life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;If you are 30 years old, thats around 300,000 hours left&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That might sound like a lot, but in the grand scheme of things, it&#39;s a precious and finite resource. Knowing that our time is limited can be a powerful motivator to make the most of every moment. It reminds us to cherish our relationships, explore the world, learn, grow, and follow our passions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every sunrise is a new opportunity, and every day is a chance to create something amazing. By recognizing the value of our limited time, we can make the most of every hour, living life to the fullest. Embrace your journey, treasure your moments, and savor the extraordinary gift of your limited life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the age I am now, if i&#39;m lucky, I have:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;life&quot;&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope I can use them well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script&gt;
	// Date future
    var date_future = new Date(&quot;01/15/2058&quot;);

	// Update the count down every 1 second
	var x = setInterval(function() {
		// Get today&#39;s date and time
		var date_now = new Date();

		// get total seconds between the times
		var delta = Math.abs(date_future - date_now) / 1000;

		// calculate (and subtract) whole hours
		var hours = Math.floor(delta / 3600);
		delta -= hours * 3600;

		// calculate (and subtract) whole minutes
		var minutes = Math.floor(delta / 60) % 60;
		delta -= minutes * 60;

		// what&#39;s left is seconds
		var seconds = Math.round(delta % 60);

		//To display the final no. of days (result)
		console.log(`${hours}h ${minutes}m ${seconds}s`);

		// Display the result in the element with id=&quot;demo&quot;
		document.getElementById(&quot;life&quot;).innerHTML = hours + &quot;h &quot;
		+ minutes + &quot;m &quot; + seconds + &quot;s &quot;;

		// If the count down is finished, write some text
		if (distance &lt; 0) {
			clearInterval(x);
			document.getElementById(&quot;life&quot;).innerHTML = &quot;EXPIRED&quot;;
		}
	}, 1000);
&lt;/script&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Dangers of Scope Creep</title>
    <link href="/posts/dangers-of-scope-creep/"/>
    <updated>2023-10-27T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>/posts/dangers-of-scope-creep/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Navigating the Tightrope of Design and Development: The Perils of Scope Creep&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meticulously organized world of tech and design, the sprint methodology has emerged as a beacon of structure and adaptability. But in this precise choreography, there&#39;s a silent menace known as scope creep that can throw even the most finely tuned projects into disarray. In this article, we&#39;ll explore the hidden dangers of scope creep in design and development sprints, with a particular focus on the burnout it can induce among team members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Understanding Scope Creep&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span&gt;Scope creep refers to the gradual, unauthorized expansion of a project&#39;s goals or features beyond its initially defined boundaries or objectives.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It starts innocently enough, with minor adjustments and additions to the project&#39;s original blueprint. These changes may seem insignificant at first, mirroring the ever-evolving nature of tech and design. However, if left unchecked, they can evolve into substantial modifications that threaten to derail the project&#39;s original objectives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Dangers of Scope Creep&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Erosion of Focus:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scope creep has a knack for diverting the team&#39;s attention away from the core objectives established at the sprint&#39;s outset. As it introduces new elements, team members find their energies scattered, hindering productivity and potentially compromising the quality of the final product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Missed Milestones:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Expanding the project&#39;s scope without extending the timeline often results in missed milestones, creating a jarring disconnect between what&#39;s planned and what&#39;s achievable. This can lead to missed deadlines and quality compromises, disrupting the delicate harmony of the sprint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Burnout Beckons:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond the evident issues of delayed timelines and quality, there&#39;s a more insidious danger: burnout. Team members, forced to navigate the complex maze of scope changes, can face excessive workloads, mental exhaustion, and stress. This burnout threatens creativity and enthusiasm, turning the sprint into an exhausting marathon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stakeholder Discontent:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the dynamic realm of tech and design, project requirements are in a perpetual state of flux. This can make it challenging to meet stakeholder expectations, leading to discord and strained relationships that can jeopardize the project&#39;s success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Mitigating Scope Creep&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Transparent Communication:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Establishing crystal-clear communication channels with stakeholders and clients is paramount. Define the project&#39;s scope, objectives, and constraints to ensure everyone understands the potential consequences of scope creep on timelines and deliverables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rigorous Documentation:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Documenting the project requirements meticulously and obtaining stakeholder sign-off is akin to creating a detailed tech blueprint. This documentation serves as a reference point to track any additional requests, guaranteeing that everyone comprehends the agreed-upon scope. Any proposed changes should undergo a formal change control process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prioritization and Collaboration:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In tech and design, prioritizing tasks and features based on their significance and alignment with the project&#39;s objectives is crucial. Collaboratively assess new requests and evaluate their compatibility with the project&#39;s goals. Engage stakeholders to maintain transparency and shared comprehension of the trade-offs related to scope alterations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Agile Adaptation:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Embrace agile principles, emphasizing flexibility and adaptability, much like adapting to new tech trends. Regularly review and refine project requirements to accommodate necessary changes while respecting the sprint&#39;s constraints.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Striking a Delicate Balance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the ever-evolving world of tech and design, scope creep is a subtle saboteur that can disrupt even the most meticulously planned projects. While it&#39;s essential to embrace adaptability and cater to evolving needs, maintaining a delicate equilibrium is equally crucial. By vigilantly monitoring scope changes, nurturing transparent communication, and prioritizing the well-being of your team members, you can navigate the treacherous waters of scope creep while warding off the looming specter of burnout. So, as you embark on your tech and design journey, remember to keep the harmony in your sprint – it&#39;s the secret to a successful and fulfilling endeavor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;case-img &quot; src=&quot;/static/images/blog/dangers-of-scope-creep/team-meeting.webp&quot; alt=&quot;team meeting everyone is happy&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@jasongoodman_youxventures?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash&quot;&gt;Jason Goodman&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/photos/man-standing-behind-flat-screen-computer-monitor-bzqU01v-G54?utm_content=creditCopyText&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_source=unsplash&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Understanding Minimalism</title>
    <link href="/posts/understanding-minimalism/"/>
    <updated>2023-09-11T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>/posts/understanding-minimalism/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Welcome&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to an exploration of minimalism, a lifestyle philosophy that advocates for simplicity, intentionality, and the pursuit of what truly matters. In a world often characterized by excess, consumerism, and constant stimulation, minimalism offers a path toward a more deliberate and uncomplicated way of living. This article delves into the connection between minimalism and the innate human desire for a simpler, more purposeful existence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Understanding Minimalism&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At its core, minimalism goes beyond a mere aesthetic preference or decluttering trend. It&#39;s a deliberate approach to living that encourages individuals to evaluate their possessions, commitments, and daily choices. By deliberately streamlining their lives, minimalists seek to focus on experiences, relationships, personal growth, and the essentials that bring genuine joy and fulfillment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;case-img &quot; src=&quot;/static/images/blog/understanding-minimalism/organised-items.webp&quot; alt=&quot;contents of bag arranged neatly next to it&quot; style=&quot;height: auto;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@minkmingle?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Mink Mingle&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/photos/zGmTRL2zH-s?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Craving for Simplicity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our modern world, marked by technological advances and information overload, there&#39;s an inherent yearning for simplicity. The desire to lead a simpler life is driven by several factors:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Information Overload:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The digital age inundates us with a constant stream of information, leading to mental fatigue and a desire to reduce the noise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Consumerism and Materialism:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pursuit of material possessions often results in clutter, financial stress, and a sense of emptiness, prompting a shift toward valuing meaningful experiences over belongings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stress and Overwhelm:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The demands of modern life can lead to stress, anxiety, and burnout. Many seek simplicity as a means to alleviate these pressures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Environmental Concerns:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Awareness of environmental issues has led many to embrace minimalism as a way to reduce their ecological footprint and contribute to sustainable living.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;case-img &quot; src=&quot;/static/images/blog/understanding-minimalism/out-in-nature.webp&quot; alt=&quot;person stood on top of mountain surrounded by nature&quot; style=&quot;height: auto;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@davidmarcu?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;David Marcu&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/photos/78A265wPiO4?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Role of Minimalism&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minimalism offers a solution to these challenges by promoting intentional living and prioritization:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Focus on Essentials:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minimalism encourages individuals to identify their core values and priorities, allowing them to declutter both physical and mental spaces and direct their energy toward what truly matters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mindful Consumption:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By adopting minimalism, individuals become more conscious of their consumption habits, opting for quality over quantity and reducing waste.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Improved Well-Being:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The decluttered living environment and reduced stress of minimalism can lead to improved mental and emotional well-being.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enhanced Relationships:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With fewer distractions, minimalists often find themselves more present in their relationships, fostering deeper connections and meaningful interactions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;case-img &quot; src=&quot;/static/images/blog/understanding-minimalism/connection-to-nature.webp&quot; alt=&quot;hands all connecting on a log in nature&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@shanerounce?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Shane Rounce&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/photos/DNkoNXQti3c?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a world where distractions abound and complexities multiply, minimalism stands as a beacon, guiding individuals toward a simpler, more meaningful life. The inherent human desire for authenticity, purpose, and tranquility finds resonance in the principles of minimalism. By shedding the unnecessary and embracing intentional choices, individuals can discover a newfound sense of contentment, clarity, and harmony within themselves and the world around them.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Mastering Layout | A Comprehensive Tutorial</title>
    <link href="/posts/mastering-ui-design-basics/"/>
    <updated>2023-08-25T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>/posts/mastering-ui-design-basics/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;User Interface &lt;em&gt;(UI)&lt;/em&gt; design plays a crucial role in crafting user-friendly digital experiences. Don&#39;t believe me? Here are some incredible UI statistics&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span&gt;94%&lt;/span&gt; of first impressions of a website is &lt;span&gt;directly related to its design&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A website is vey often one of the first real interactions that your potential customers will have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;span&gt;Initial judgment&lt;/span&gt; on a website&#39;s credibility is &lt;span&gt;75% based on its overall aesthetics&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial, we&#39;ll delve into the fundamental principles of layouts, covering grids, line length, margins, rule of thirds, type sizes, alignment and spacing. By understanding the reasons behind these practices, you&#39;ll be better equipped to create engaging user interfaces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Grids: Laying the foundations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grids are the hidden architecture of almost all forms of graphic, print and web design. It is used to get an idea of the composition and structure, or &#39;feel&#39;, of a page. Implementing thoughtful layouts offers several advantages:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feel for design early:&lt;/strong&gt; using simple grid guidelines you can start to see an outline of what you are going to make. This helps to set the building blocks of the design while the lines are still loose and easy ot change. An effective layout provides a clear structure and helps users navigate content with ease.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;User-Focused Flow:&lt;/strong&gt; A well-designed layout guides users through the content in a natural and intuitive sequence.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Improved Scannability:&lt;/strong&gt; A structured layout enables users to quickly scan and locate information, improving usability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Rule of thirds&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Rule of Thirds is a basic principle in photography, art, and design that helps create visually appealing and balanced compositions. It involves dividing an image into nine equal parts by overlaying two equally spaced horizontal lines and two equally spaced vertical lines, resulting in a grid with four intersections points.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;case-img &quot; src=&quot;/static/images/blog/mastering-ui-design-basics/rule-of-thirds-car-parking-garage.webp&quot; alt=&quot;rule of thirds car parking garage&quot; style=&quot;height: auto;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Example rule of thirds&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Line length: Keeping people interested&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever noticed that Google results &lt;em&gt;(desktop)&lt;/em&gt; have a really thin width despite it being a massive white page. It&#39;s to make the results scannable. &lt;strong&gt;Columns of text should have a minimum of 6 words&lt;/strong&gt;. This will make the text you are reading feel less jittery and more structured.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shorter lines are more comfortable to read than longer lines. As line length increases, your eye has to travel farther from the end of one line to the beginning of the next, making it harder to track your progress vertically. &lt;strong&gt;Aim for an average line length of 45–90 characters, including spaces&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;case-img &quot; src=&quot;/static/images/blog/mastering-ui-design-basics/columns-in-paper.webp&quot; alt=&quot;man reading newspaper&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@iamromankraft?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Roman Kraft&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/photos/_Zua2hyvTBk?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Alignment: Achieving Visual Harmony&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alignment is a cornerstone of good design, bringing a sense of order and visual harmony to your interface. When elements are aligned, users can easily process and navigate your content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;case-img &quot; src=&quot;/static/images/blog/mastering-ui-design-basics/alignment-scrabble.webp&quot; alt=&quot;alignment scrabble&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@edznorton?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Edz Norton&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/photos/ofja_9Ud9i0?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enhances Readability:&lt;/strong&gt; Aligned text and images are easier to read and comprehend.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Creates Balance:&lt;/strong&gt; Symmetrically aligned elements create a sense of balance and professionalism.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aids Scannability:&lt;/strong&gt; Aligned elements guide users&#39; eyes along a logical path, improving content consumption.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Spacing: Consistency and Proportion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maintaining consistent spacing is more than just a design rule, it serves practical purposes that contribute to a polished design. &lt;strong&gt;At school we were taught to use increments of 8px across web designs&lt;/strong&gt;. This allows everything on the page to look related and as it had a lot of multiples you can get away with using lots of values that are still related. You can often see this principle mimicked in css frameworks, such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://tailwindcss.com/&quot;&gt;Tailwind&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enhances Readability:&lt;/strong&gt; Proper spacing prevents elements from crowding, ensuring text and images are easily distinguishable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Provides Structure:&lt;/strong&gt; Multiples of 8 create a structured layout that aligns with users&#39; expectations, making it easier to navigate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Achieves Proportion:&lt;/strong&gt; Consistent spacing fosters a sense of proportion, guiding users&#39; attention to the right elements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Margins: Creating Breathing Space&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Margins are not just empty gaps; they contribute to the overall design&#39;s cohesiveness and user experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;case-img &quot; src=&quot;/static/images/blog/mastering-ui-design-basics/spacing-layout.webp&quot; alt=&quot;spacing on a brochure&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@plhnk?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Paul Hanaoka&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/photos/zxn5g_aZYTQ?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Visual Separation:&lt;/strong&gt; Margins create a clear separation between elements, the more related an item, the closer the margins. Reducing visual clutter massively improves legibility.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aesthetic Appeal:&lt;/strong&gt; Ample margins give your design a clean and sophisticated look, making it visually appealing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Focus and Attention:&lt;/strong&gt; Well-placed margins draw attention to essential elements, directing users&#39; focus effectively.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Whitespace: Embracing Simplicity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whitespace is a powerful tool that offers several benefits for both aesthetics and usability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;case-img &quot; src=&quot;/static/images/blog/mastering-ui-design-basics/white-space.webp&quot; alt=&quot;blank booklets&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@mediamodifier?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Mediamodifier&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/photos/yev5EPcUtyc?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clarity and Focus:&lt;/strong&gt; Whitespace allows users to focus on the content by reducing distractions and visual noise.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Improved Readability:&lt;/strong&gt; Ample whitespace around text enhances readability and comprehension.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Elegance and Sophistication:&lt;/strong&gt; Thoughtful use of whitespace conveys a sense of elegance and professionalism.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Type sizes: Showing Heirarchy&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Then you can show something less important with h2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Now a h3&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Getting small at h4&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Tiny at h5: much less important&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;Basically ignore this h6&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By organizing elements hierarchically, you emphasize key content and facilitate user engagement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding the reasons behind UI design principles empowers you to create awesome interfaces. By embracing these practices, you ensure that your designs are user-centric, intuitive, and visually pleasing. Remember, while these principles provide a solid set of foundations, always adapt them to suit your project&#39;s specific needs, and let your creativity shine as you craft remarkable digital interfaces.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Understanding Image Extensions in Graphic and Web Design</title>
    <link href="/posts/understanding-image-extensions-in-graphic-and-web-design/"/>
    <updated>2023-08-24T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>/posts/understanding-image-extensions-in-graphic-and-web-design/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In the realm of graphic and web design, choosing the right image format can significantly impact the quality, loading speed, and overall user experience. In fact, per recent statistics, &lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt; in &lt;strong&gt;4&lt;/strong&gt; visitors would leave a site that takes more than &lt;strong&gt;4 seconds&lt;/strong&gt; to load.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Every &lt;span&gt;1 second&lt;/span&gt; delay reduces user satisfaction by &lt;span&gt;16%&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Different image extensions &lt;em&gt;(.svg, .png, .jpg, etc.)&lt;/em&gt; cater to varying needs, making it essential to understand their characteristics and best use cases. In this blog post, we&#39;ll explore the most common image formats and how they are utilized in graphic and web design and development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;.SVG (Scalable Vector Graphics)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SVG is a vector-based image format that uses XML-based markup language to define two-dimensional graphics. One of its key advantages is scalability; SVG images can be resized without loss of quality, making them ideal for responsive web design, logos, and icons. Moreover, they have small file sizes, resulting in faster loading times. Since SVG is supported by most modern browsers, it&#39;s an excellent choice for graphics that need to look sharp on any device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;case-img&quot; src=&quot;/static/images/blog/understanding-image-extensions-in-graphic-and-web-design/bond-street-logo.webp&quot; alt=&quot;bond street logo&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@richwilliamsmith?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Rich Smith&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/photos/lVVs5skyWoo?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;When to use&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Logo for a Tech Startup&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Suppose you&#39;re designing a logo for a tech startup that will be used on their website, mobile app, and promotional materials. Using SVG format ensures that the logo remains sharp and legible, regardless of the screen size or resolution.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Responsive Icons for a Mobile App&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;When designing icons for a mobile app, you want them to adapt seamlessly to different screen sizes. SVG icons provide this flexibility, maintaining clarity and consistency across various devices.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Designing for print&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;When designing for print, such as t-shirt graphics, van decals or billboards, it helps to use an SVG as it can scale to fit all product sizes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;.PNG (Portable Network Graphics)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PNG is a lossless raster image format known for its ability to preserve image quality without compression artifacts. It supports transparent backgrounds, making it ideal for logos, icons, and images with irregular shapes. PNG&#39;s lossless nature comes at the cost of a larger file sizes, making it less suitable for large photographs. In graphic and web design, PNGs are widely used for graphics that require transparency or sharp details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;case-img&quot; src=&quot;/static/images/blog/understanding-image-extensions-in-graphic-and-web-design/instagram-png.png&quot; alt=&quot;instagram logo png&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;PNG example - it usually doesnt have the checkered background but I wanted it to be more visual.
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;When to use&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Logo with Transparency:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Imagine designing a logo with a unique shape that needs to be displayed on various colored backgrounds. Using a PNG format with a transparent background ensures that the logo blends seamlessly with different page designs.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Icon Set for a Website:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you&#39;re creating a set of icons to be used on a website, PNG format is perfect for retaining the icons&#39; sharpness and details, especially when they have small intricate elements.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;.JPG (Joint Photographic Experts Group)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JPG, also known as JPEG, is a popular lossy image format that significantly compresses image data to reduce file sizes. As a result, it may compromise some image quality, especially in high-compression settings. Despite this, JPG is widely used for photographs and images on the web, where the trade-off between quality and file size is necessary for faster loading times. It is not recommended for images with text or graphics requiring transparency, as artifacts may occur.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;case-img&quot; src=&quot;/static/images/blog/understanding-image-extensions-in-graphic-and-web-design/web-gallery-images.webp&quot; alt=&quot;web gallery on desktop&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@anniespratt?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Annie Spratt&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/photos/jFtBa6aEJqk?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;When to use&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Website Banner Image:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;When selecting an image for a website banner that contains a photograph or intricate artwork, JPG format strikes a balance between image quality and file size, ensuring a visually appealing and fast-loading webpage.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Product Gallery Images for an Online Store:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In an e-commerce website displaying various products, JPG format is preferred for product images, allowing customers to see product details without causing long load times.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;.GIF (Graphics Interchange Format)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GIF is a legacy format primarily used for animated images. It supports simple animations, but its color palette is limited to 256 colors, leading to lower image quality. GIFs are commonly used for small animations, memes, and icons that require minimal colors and transparency. However, for larger animations and higher-quality graphics, other formats like .webp or .mp4 are more suitable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;case-img&quot; src=&quot;/static/images/blog/understanding-image-extensions-in-graphic-and-web-design/goose-gif.gif&quot; alt=&quot;cartoon walking goose gif&quot; style=&quot;height: auto;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;A fun goose gif
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;When to use&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Loading Spinner Animation:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Incorporating a loading spinner animation on a website is a great use of GIF format, as it can be small in size and doesn&#39;t require a wide range of colors.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Animated Social Media Icon:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;When creating an animated social media icon that subtly moves or changes colors, GIF format is perfect for adding that touch of interactivity.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;.WEBP&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developed by Google, WEBP is a relatively new image format that combines both lossy and lossless compression. It offers better image quality and smaller file sizes than JPG and PNG. While WEBP is becoming increasingly supported in modern browsers, it&#39;s essential to provide fallback options for browsers that do not support it, usually through the use of the &#39;picture&#39; HTML element.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;case-img&quot; src=&quot;/static/images/blog/understanding-image-extensions-in-graphic-and-web-design/image-gallery-on-phone.webp&quot; alt=&quot;image gallery on mobile phone&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@brookelark?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Brooke Lark&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/photos/W1B2LpQOBxA?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;When to use&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Featured Image for a Blog Post:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;When optimizing a blog post&#39;s featured image for faster loading and improved SEO, using WEBP format ensures a smaller file size without compromising image quality.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Photo Gallery on a Mobile App:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you&#39;re designing a photo gallery for a mobile app, using WEBP format for images enhances the app&#39;s performance, allowing users to browse through pictures smoothly.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In graphic and web design and development, choosing the appropriate image format is crucial to optimize loading times, enhance user experience, and maintain image quality. SVGs work best for scalable graphics like logos and icons, while PNGs are preferred for images with transparent backgrounds. JPGs are ideal for photographic content when balancing quality and file size, while GIFs are useful for small animations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;As the web evolves, formats like WEBP are gaining popularity, offering a &lt;span&gt;compromise between lossy and lossless compression&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding these image extensions empowers designers and developers to make informed choices, ensuring their visuals look their best across all platforms and devices. Happy designing!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Samsung Galaxy Tab S6 Lite review | The Best Budget Drawing Tablet</title>
    <link href="/posts/samsung-galaxy-tab-s6-lite-review/"/>
    <updated>2023-08-16T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>/posts/samsung-galaxy-tab-s6-lite-review/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As someone interested in design &lt;em&gt;(I assume that is why you are reading)&lt;/em&gt; and access to the infinite stream of social meida I&#39;m sure you must have seen peopel on YouTube, Instagram and TikTok doing amazing digital drawings and animations with their brand new iPads or graphics tablets that cost more than most people make in a month. If you have, I&#39;m sure you have wished you could give it a go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Enter the Samsung Galaxy Tab S6 Lite! It is a remarkable device that stands out as the best budget drawing tablet in the market today.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Packed with impressive features and a competitive price point, this tablet is an excellent choice for both aspiring artists and seasoned professionals who are looking for an affordable yet powerful drawing tool. Below I will go into some of the reasons I think it can work for you too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Design and Build Quality&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Galaxy Tab S6 Lite boasts a sleek and modern design that is both lightweight and compact, making it highly portable and easy to carry around. Its build quality is solid, with a sturdy metal frame that gives it a premium feel without compromising on durability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Display and Stylus&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tablet&#39;s display is an LCD with a resolution of 2000 x 1200 pixels, which delivers crisp and vibrant visuals. Though not as advanced as OLED displays found in higher-end tablets, it still offers an impressive color accuracy and sufficient brightness for most artistic needs. Additionally, the Galaxy Tab S6 Lite comes with an included S Pen stylus, which is a fantastic bonus. The S Pen is sensitive, accurate, and supports tilt functionality, making drawing on this tablet a delightful experience. The device&#39;s 10.4-inch display is the perfect size for drawing, providing ample screen real estate for creativity to flourish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Performance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Powered by Samsung&#39;s Exynos 9611 octa-core processor and 4GB of RAM, the Galaxy Tab S6 Lite delivers commendable performance for its price point. It handles drawing apps and multitasking with ease, ensuring smooth strokes and quick response times while working on intricate art projects. While it may not match the sheer power of high-end tablets, for a budget drawing tablet, its performance is more than satisfactory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Drawing Experience&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a drawing tablet, the Galaxy Tab S6 Lite excels. Whether you&#39;re sketching, painting, or doing digital illustrations, the combination of the S Pen and the tablet&#39;s display offers an intuitive and fluid drawing experience. The pressure sensitivity of the S Pen is particularly impressive, allowing artists to create varying line thicknesses and achieve subtle shading effects effortlessly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;case-img &quot; src=&quot;/static/images/blog/samsung-galaxy-tab-s6-lite-review/samsung-galaxy-s-pen.webp&quot; alt=&quot;samsung galaxy s-pen&quot; style=&quot;height: auto;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Samsung Galaxy S-Pen&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are also a range of fantastic apps on the Google Play Store for drawing (&lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=org.krita&quot;&gt;Krita&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.adsk.sketchbook&quot;&gt;Sketchbook&lt;/a&gt;) and apps for animation (&lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.vblast.flipaclip&quot;&gt;FlipaClip&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Software and Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tablet runs on Samsung&#39;s One UI 2.0 based on Android, which provides a user-friendly interface with access to a wide range of drawing and creative apps from the Google Play Store. Samsung also offers its suite of creative tools that enhance the drawing experience further. Furthermore, the tablet supports Samsung DeX, enabling a desktop-like experience when connected to an external display.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Battery Life&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Galaxy Tab S6 Lite boasts a sizable 7040mAh battery that can easily last through a day of moderate to heavy use. For artists who enjoy long drawing sessions, the tablet&#39;s impressive battery life is a significant advantage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Price&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Price is a big one for everyone, especially as bread is now twice the price it was last year and the Galaxy Tab S6 Lite comes at a really resonable cost. I myself managed to pick one up from &lt;a href=&quot;https://uk.webuy.com/&quot;&gt;CEX&lt;/a&gt; for just £170 quid and if you are willing to wait around on something like Facebook marketplace that price will drop even further!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Negatives&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing is perfect and I do think with a cheaper tablet there are a couple of trade offs that you have to make:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Limited Processing Power: While the tablet is sufficient for most drawing applications and tasks, it may struggle with more demanding software or large, complex art projects. Users who plan to use resource-intensive applications or multitask extensively might experience occasional lag or slower performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Non-Laminated Display: Unlike some higher-end tablets, the Galaxy Tab S6 Lite does not feature a laminated display. This means that there can be a slight gap between the glass and the actual screen, leading to a perception of parallax when drawing. While this might not be a significant issue for casual artists, it can be a minor annoyance for those seeking a more precise and seamless drawing experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, the Samsung Galaxy Tab S6 Lite unquestionably stands as the best budget drawing tablet on the market. Its combination of a vibrant display, excellent stylus performance, solid build quality, and strong battery life makes it a compelling choice for artists on a budget. While it may not have the top-tier specs of high-end tablets, its overall performance and features make it a true value-for-money drawing companion. Whether you&#39;re a budding artist or a professional looking for a secondary drawing device, the Galaxy Tab S6 Lite will not disappoint, especially with its competitive price point that opens up opportunities for artists of all skill levels to embrace digital artistry without sacrificing quality.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Doves in the Thames</title>
    <link href="/posts/doves-in-the-thames/"/>
    <updated>2023-08-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>/posts/doves-in-the-thames/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Of all the reasons to stop using a font, having it drown is probably the most remarkable.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Typography is an art form that weaves letters into captivating narratives. The Doves typeface is a testament to the power of typography to tell a story beyond words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are about to embark on a captivating journey through the fascinating history of the Doves Roman typeface – a revival that breathed new life into a lost treasure of the printing world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Birth of Doves Typeface (Early 1900s):&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our story begins in the early twentieth century, specifically in the year 1900, when two visionaries, Thomas James Cobden-Sanderson and Emery Walker, embarked on a collaborative project that would shape the future of typography. They founded &#39;THE DOVES PRESS&#39;, which During nearly seventeen years of operation, produced some of the finest &amp;amp; most notable examples of twentieth century typography to date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The crown jewel of this was the Doves typeface. It owed its aesthetic roots to the pioneering work of Nicolas Jenson, a Venetian printer from the fifteenth century. Percy Tiffin&#39;s drawings, based on Jenson&#39;s innovative Venetian type, served as the foundation for the Doves typeface&#39;s graceful curves, clean lines, and classic proportions. This historical lineage added a layer of depth and connection to the Doves typeface, imbuing it with the spirit of centuries past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;case-img &quot; src=&quot;/static/images/blog/doves-in-the-thames/type.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bold color&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Before digital media to create a font family each letter, in every thickness, in upper and lowercase, and all of the accompanying punctuiation had to be created using metal or wood. Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@fabiosbruun?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Fabio Santaniello Bruun&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/photos/Y6tGu-OH8lA?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The task of bringing this vision to life fell into the hands of master punchcutter Edward Prince, who meticulously translated drawings produced by Percy Tiffin into the intricate metal type that would become known as the Doves typeface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Partnership dissolved (1908)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the Doves Press flourished, so did the creative tensions between its founders. When the partnership was formally dissolved in 1909, a legal agreement was drawn up whereby the two men would share the type; Cobden-Sanderson could retain its exclusive use (including all the type punches and matrices needed to print) to continue printing Doves Press publications until his death, whereupon ownership would then pass to Walker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;A Drastic Decision (1916):&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Determined to safeguard the integrity of the Doves typeface, Cobden-Sanderson took drastic action. He embarked on a mission that would ultimately shape the legacy of the typeface – a mission to physically destroy the metal type and matrices that comprised the Doves typeface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The River Thames Affair (1917-1918):&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From 1917 to 1918, Cobden-Sanderson executed his audacious plan with meticulous precision. Under the cover of darkness, he cast the metal type and matrices from the Hammersmith Bridge into the River Thames, one piece at a time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the next 5 months, he had made the half mile trip more than a hundred seperate times (at this point he was seventy-six!), hauling over a ton of type, until it was gone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;case-img &quot; src=&quot;/static/images/blog/doves-in-the-thames/bridge.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bold color&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Hammersmith bridge, London &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@hdong?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Hao Dong&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/photos/htL4eqkuDa4?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This clandestine act was an embodiment of Cobden-Sanderson&#39;s unwavering commitment to the exclusivity of the Doves typeface. As the metal sank into the river&#39;s depths, it marked the end of an era and the beginning of a mysterious chapter in the typeface&#39;s history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Decades of Obscurity and Rediscovery (20th-21st Century):&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following its watery interment, the Doves typeface slipped into obscurity. The typeface remained hidden beneath the river&#39;s surface, its story known to only a few passionate typographic historians. However, in 2014, the tides of fate shifted once again. Robert Green, a designer and typographer, stumbled upon remnants of the Doves typeface in the muddy banks of the Thames. This serendipitous discovery ignited a renewed interest in the typeface and set the stage for a remarkable revival.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Revival (2014-Present):&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Green&#39;s discovery rekindled the flame of fascination with the Doves typeface. Driven by a deep respect for its historical significance, Green embarked on a painstaking journey to recreate the lost typeface. Armed with surviving printed material, historical records, and modern digital tools, Green meticulously reconstructed the Doves typeface character by character. His dedication breathed new life into the typeface, capturing its essence and enabling it to grace modern publications and designs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Legacy Lives On:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, the Doves typeface stands as a living testament to the enduring power of typography. Green&#39;s revival efforts have ensured that this once-lost treasure continues to captivate and inspire designers, typographers, and enthusiasts alike. The Doves Type Revival project, born from a desire to honor the legacy of Cobden-Sanderson and Walker&#39;s creation, has bridged the gap between history and innovation, preserving the beauty and craftsmanship of a bygone era for generations to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The tale of the Doves typeface is a captivating narrative that spans centuries, continents, and the depths of a river.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From its birth as a collaborative vision in the early 1900s to its revival and continued relevance in the twenty-first century, the Doves typeface exemplifies the profound impact of art and dedication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This tale reminds us that even lost art forms can be resurrected, inviting us to traverse the river of time and appreciate the intricate beauty of typographic craftsmanship.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Top Prototyping Tools for Ux / UI Designers</title>
    <link href="/posts/top-prototyping-tools-for-ux-ui-designers/"/>
    <updated>2023-08-09T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>/posts/top-prototyping-tools-for-ux-ui-designers/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Top 5 prototyping tools&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the rise of Ux / UI design industry, designers are looking for tools that will help them bring their design ideas to life in the most efficient way possible. Prototyping tools have become an essential part of a Ux / UI designer&#39;s toolset, allowing them to create high-fidelity prototypes that give stakeholders an idea of what the final product will look like. This not only saves a lot of time for product develoopment but also a lot of money as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Here are my recommendations as someone who has used these tools everyday for the last 4 years.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;5. UXPin&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;case-img&quot; src=&quot;/static/images/blog/top-prototyping-tools-for-ux-ui-designers/uxpin.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;uxpin user interface screenshot&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;UXPin user interface screenshot&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.uxpin.com/&quot;&gt;UXPin&lt;/a&gt; is a comprehensive design and prototyping platform. It offers a lot of the things you would expect out of the box, allowing you to create clean prototypes, with the added bonus of advanced prototyping features, to create lifelike interactions, animations, and responsive designs, ensuring a realistic user testing environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UXPin&#39;s design system capabilities enhance consistency and efficiency by enabling the creation and management of reusable design components and libraries. This ensures a cohesive user interface across various screens and projects, saving valuable time and effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While UXPin&#39;s feature-rich environment caters to experienced designers, it has a much steeper learning curve for beginners. I also find that this product is a bit better at the design system side of things than perhaps for prototyping. However, its extensive documentation, tutorials, and customer support help mitigate this challenge. If you are trying to optimize design flow across a company UXPin can import Figma designs and export them into Storybook. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.uxpin.com/sign-up&quot;&gt;Try it free here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;4. Sketch&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;case-img&quot; src=&quot;/static/images/blog/top-prototyping-tools-for-ux-ui-designers/sketch.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;sketch user interface screenshot&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Sketch user interface screenshot&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sketch.com/&quot;&gt;Sketch&lt;/a&gt; is a popular vector-based design tool tailored for modern interface and user experience design. Offering an intuitive and efficient environment, Sketch enables designers to create visually appealing and responsive layouts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its focus on user interfaces, symbols, and artboards streamlines the design process, while plugins enhance functionality and integration with other tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sketch&#39;s powerful features, simplicity, and community support make it a go-to choice for UI/UX designers seeking to design and prototype websites, mobile apps, and digital interfaces with precision and ease. However, I am unable to give it a high spot as it is primarily available on macOS which is very limiting. Can&#39;t find a free trial (classic Apple product) but &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sketch.com/pricing/&quot;&gt;pricing options are here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;3. Adobe XD&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;case-img&quot; src=&quot;/static/images/blog/top-prototyping-tools-for-ux-ui-designers/xd.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;adobe xd software on laptop&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@elisebouet?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Elise Bouet&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/photos/HeuT_HhBdB8?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adobe XD is a powerful and versatile design tool that offers an impressive array of features for creating interactive prototypes, user interfaces, and user experiences. It has gained popularity among designers and UX professionals for its intuitive interface and seamless integration with other Adobe Creative Cloud applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Adobe XD offers a host of advantages, it&#39;s worth noting that it may have a steeper learning curve for those who are new to design tools or have not used other Adobe products before. Some users might miss certain advanced features present in other design tools, but Adobe XD&#39;s regular updates and feature additions are addressing these gaps over time. Adobe XD used to be free in beta, butr has since been absorbed into the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.adobe.com/uk/creativecloud.html&quot;&gt;Adobe Creative Cloud&lt;/a&gt; suite, making using this a bit more of an investment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;2. Axure RP&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;case-img&quot; src=&quot;/static/images/blog/top-prototyping-tools-for-ux-ui-designers/rp.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;axure rp user interface screenshot&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Axure RP user interface screenshot&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.axure.com/&quot;&gt;Axure RP&lt;/a&gt; is a versatile and robust prototyping tool aimed at creating interactive, dynamic, and detailed wireframes and prototypes. With a user-centric approach, Axure RP allows designers to simulate complex interactions, animations, and user flows, providing an authentic testing environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its drag-and-drop interface, coupled with powerful features like conditional logic and adaptive views, enables the creation of sophisticated and responsive prototypes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While offering a rich array of capabilities, Axure RP might require a learning curve for beginners. Nonetheless, its ability to bridge the gap between design and development makes it a valuable choice for UX/UI professionals aiming to craft highly interactive and realistic prototypes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I personally realy like this app and if it was more commonly used I think it would be top spot. If you do want to try it out there is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.axure.com/download&quot;&gt;free trial here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;1. Figma&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;case-img&quot; src=&quot;/static/images/blog/top-prototyping-tools-for-ux-ui-designers/figma.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;figma website on laptop&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@tracycodes?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Tracy Adams&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/photos/rA5MU4pXnWE?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.figma.com/&quot;&gt;Figma&lt;/a&gt; is a cloud-based design tool that allows teams to collaborate on design projects in real-time. One of the standout features of Figma is its ability to create design systems as well as prototype. With no coding knowledge required, designers can create and maintain design systems efficiently. Figma&#39;s collaborative features also make it easier to share and iterate on design components. One of the standout features of Figma is the plugins. I have found that Figma has the best range of community plugins to achieve almost anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Figma offers a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.figma.com/pricing/&quot;&gt;free trial&lt;/a&gt; with, 3 Figma and 3 FigJam files, unlimited personal files, unlimited collaborators, and access to plugins and templates. I would definitely recommend this as a good place to start learning as it is very intuitive to use and is quickly becoming the industry standard for UI design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a UX/UI designer, choosing the right prototyping tool can greatly impact your productivity and the quality of your work. The tools listed above are some of the most popular prototyping tools used by designers today. Each of these tools has its own unique features and benefits, so it&#39;s essential to choose a tool that fits your needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to stay ahead in the industry, it&#39;s vital to stay up-to-date with the latest prototyping tools and trends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Honorable mentions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Marvel app&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://marvelapp.com/&quot;&gt;The Marvel app&lt;/a&gt; allows designers to easily transform really low-fidelity and messy ideas into dynamic, clickable mockups, enabling effective communication and collaboration among teams. With its user-friendly features, Marvel simplifies the process of iterating and refining designs, facilitating efficient workflows in web and app development. It empowers designers to visualize and showcase their concepts, enhancing the overall design process and enabling a more engaging end-user experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;InVison Studio&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.invisionapp.com/&quot;&gt;InVision Studio&lt;/a&gt; is a powerful prototyping tool that allows designers to create rich interactive prototypes. It has a user-friendly interface that makes it easy for designers to create complex animations and interactions. InVision Studio also has an extensive design library with built-in UI kits, icons, and more. It also has collaboration features that allow designers to share their work with stakeholders for feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Origami Studio&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://origami.design/&quot;&gt;Origami Studio&lt;/a&gt; is a prototyping tool that is used for designing interactions and animations. It is primarily used for creating mobile app prototypes. Origami Studio has a user-friendly interface that includes drag-and-drop functionality, making it easy for designers to create complex animations. It also has a plugin system that allows designers to extend its functionality.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>The Rise of Eco-Friendly Design</title>
    <link href="/posts/the-rise-of-eco-friendly-design/"/>
    <updated>2023-07-24T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>/posts/the-rise-of-eco-friendly-design/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Perhaps it&#39;s been the numerous forest fires or record breaking temperatures, but, in recent years, there has been a significant shift in consumer consciousness. More and more people are becoming aware of the environmental impact of their choices. As a result, the demand for eco-friendly and sustainable products has soared. This has prompted industries to finally reevaluate their practices now that money is to be grubbed from consumers under the guise of noble business practice. The design industry, in particular, has been shaken up by this challenge, forcing designers to embrace sustainability as a driving force in the creative processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this blog post, we will explore how designers are responding to the call for eco-friendly design, from innovative eco-packaging solutions to the rise of environmentally conscious web design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Eco-Packaging: A Greener Approach to Packaging Design&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traditional packaging has long been a major contributor to environmental pollution, generating vast amounts of waste that often ends up in landfills or our oceans. This has irritated me to point that this was in fact the thesis for my &lt;em&gt;rejected&lt;/em&gt; PHD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eco-friendly design aims to minimize this impact by adopting greener practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;case-img&quot; src=&quot;/static/images/blog/the-rise-of-eco-friendly-design/packaging.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;eco-friendly packaging&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@marcellviragh?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Marcell Viragh&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/photos/3ah83oHlmKc?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sustainable Materials: Designers are increasingly turning to sustainable materials such as recycled paper, biodegradable plastics, and plant-based inks. These materials not only reduce the carbon footprint but also provide a unique and eco-conscious touch to product packaging. Using materials that can be infintiely recycled (essentially metal and glass) helps to prevent need for new material extraction, diverts from landfill and uses much less energy to produce. Read more about this &lt;a href=&quot;https://lochtree.com/blogs/blog/infinitely-recyclable-materials-what-are-they-and-does-it-matter&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; if this has ticked the right hemisphere of your brain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minimalist Design: Thanks to current trends, embracing minimalism in packaging design helps reduce material usage, reduce manufacturing complexity and reduce waste while creating a sleek and sophisticated look that resonates with many consumers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reusability and Upcycling: Designers are exploring innovative ways to design packaging that can be reused or repurposed, extending the life cycle of the materials and minimizing waste. I went looking for some examples and decided that this would make a pretty cool follow up post, so now you have to wait.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sustainable Product Design: Form and Function with the Environment in Mind&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond packaging, eco-friendly design is influencing the creation of sustainable products across various industries. From furniture made with reclaimed wood to energy-efficient electronics, the focus is on both form and function, without compromising on environmental responsibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are near Bristol, visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://sparksbristol.co.uk/&quot;&gt;SPARKS&lt;/a&gt;. Sparks Bristol is a department store designed to support people in Bristol to take easy (and often money-saving!) actions on climate, equality and wellbeing. It is really innovative and interesting!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cradle-to-Cradle Design (C2C): C2C is a variant of the corporate cradle-to-grave, creating a product&#39;s lifecycle with the assumption it will end in a grave (landfill). Following the cradle-to-cradle approach, designers are designing products with materials that can be easily recycled or biodegraded, ensuring a circular economy and reducing the strain on natural resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Energy Efficiency: Electronics and appliances are being designed with energy efficiency in mind, helping consumers reduce their energy consumption and carbon footprint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Environmentally Conscious Web Design: Digital Sustainability Matters&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eco-friendly design has also extended its long green thumbs into the digital realm, with designers recognizing the significance of reducing the environmental impact of websites and digital products and consumers choosing to support those that do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;case-img&quot; src=&quot;/static/images/blog/the-rise-of-eco-friendly-design/server.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;servers at data center&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@tvick?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Taylor Vick&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/photos/M5tzZtFCOfs?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Green Hosting: Designers are choosing web hosting services that run on renewable energy sources, minimizing the carbon emissions associated with website hosting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Optimize for Speed and Efficiency: By optimizing websites for faster loading times, designers can reduce energy consumption and enable a smoother user experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eco-Friendly UX: Intuitive and user-friendly interfaces help reduce the time users spend navigating a website, resulting in lower energy usage. There is a bit of a trade off here because many websites are still designed to keep you browsing for as long as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the world continues to grapple with environmental challenges, the design industry plays a pivotal role in shaping a sustainable future. Embracing eco-friendly design practices, from eco-packaging solutions to environmentally conscious web design, not only reduces our ecological footprint but also sends a powerful message to consumers. By prioritizing sustainability, designers are demonstrating their commitment to creating a more environmentally responsible and resilient world. As consumers, we hold the power to support these initiatives by choosing eco-friendly products and embracing a greener lifestyle. Together, we can drive the rise of eco-friendly design and pave the way towards a more sustainable future.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>The Pros and Cons of Remote Working as a Designer</title>
    <link href="/posts/the-pros-and-cons-of-remote-working-as-a-designer/"/>
    <updated>2023-04-20T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>/posts/the-pros-and-cons-of-remote-working-as-a-designer/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Certain events have drastically changed how we work over the last few years, with remote working becoming more and more common. As a digital designer, you often have the option to work remotely, but is it the right choice?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we will have a look at the dizzying highs and terrifying lows of remote working as a designer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Pros of Remote Working as a Designer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Flexibility&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remote working provides the flexibility that many crave in their work-life balance. As a designer, you can work from anywhere in the world, or indeed anywhere in your house. It allows you to easily work around other commitments or even travel while still getting your work done. For people looking for the perfect work life balance this is defintely a great start!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than that, without having to commute, you can avoid those long days where you set of to work in the dark and return in the dark. The flexibilty and comfort of your own home can also be a great boost to mental wellbeing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;case-img &quot; src=&quot;/static/images/blog/the-pros-and-cons-of-remote-working-as-a-designer/anywhere.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;working by the sea&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Working by the sea: Photo by Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/fr/@seefromthesky?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Ishan @seefromthesky&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/photos/c2CUKwbKQPg?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Increased Productivity&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://resources.owllabs.com/hubfs/SORW/SORW_2021/owl-labs_state-of-remote-work-2021_report-final.pdf?utm_campaign=State%20of%20Remote%20Work%202021&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;_hsmi=180908804&amp;amp;_hsenc=p2ANqtz-_QqLl-7bQetJbJYOdCoskUzSr2pErrPvrTL353dUDu9e3aetTHyMlktMDf-N_opd0g0eg2lZzzzMM4MFaCkoOPa9Edt73hZO7QXJGYUaOVMIId_nk&amp;amp;utm_content=180908804&amp;amp;utm_source=hs_automation&quot;&gt;Studies have shown that remote workers are more productive than office workers&lt;/a&gt;. Without the distractions of a busy office, and being osmewhere comfortable, remote workers are often able to focus better on their work, leading to better productivity levels. Being able to put on the washing machine during a break also means you can get a lotn of chores done before the day is even over maximising relaxation time in the evening!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Cost Savings&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remote working can provide a massive cost savings for both the employee and the employer. As a designer, you can save money on transportation, meals, and even work attire. Employers can also save on office costs like rent, electricity, and water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Cons of Remote Working as a Designer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Lack of Face-to-Face Interaction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remote working can definitely lead to feelings of isolation. While Team calls can achieve a little, they do not fill the void caused by a lack of face-to-face interaction with colleagues and collaborators. Teams isnt quite as good. This can be especially difficult for designers, who often rely on collaboration and feedback from others. Maybe the Metaverse will be our saviour, though I tend to doubt it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;case-img &quot; src=&quot;/static/images/blog/the-pros-and-cons-of-remote-working-as-a-designer/meta.png&quot; alt=&quot;metaverse&quot; style=&quot;height: auto;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Metaverse&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Communication Challenges&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Communication can be more difficult in a remote working environment, and it can be challenging to keep everyone on the same page. Misunderstandings can occur more easily when communication is done solely through email or instant messaging and when trying to lead collaborative sessions or work with users it can feel a little bit disconnected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are tools to help. &lt;a href=&quot;https://miro.com&quot;&gt;Miro&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.figma.com/&quot;&gt;Figma&lt;/a&gt; are especially helpful for collaborating with others in real time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;case-img &quot; src=&quot;/static/images/blog/the-pros-and-cons-of-remote-working-as-a-designer/figma.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Figma&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Figma: Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/ja/@ion66574?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Ion (Ivan) Sipilov&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/photos/Z8Fm-Dc3G7A?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Distractions at Home&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While it can be more productive, working from home can also be challenging if there are distractions present, like pets or family members. It can be difficult to balance work responsibilities with home responsibilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;case-img &quot; src=&quot;/static/images/blog/the-pros-and-cons-of-remote-working-as-a-designer/cat.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cat on laptop&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Cat on laptop: Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@agforl24?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Tai Bui&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/photos/393l7SYoM7w?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remote working can be a great option for designers, but it does come with its own set of challenges. It provides flexibility, cost savings, and increased productivity, but it can easily lead to isolation, communication challenges, and distractions at home. Perhaps the real winning solution is a combination of the two, allowing you flexibilty on the days where you don&#39;t want to leave the comfot of home and the chance to go into the office when pets and children are being annoying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider what is most important to you. Will the benefits outweigh the challenges? Only you can decide.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Design Trends 2023 - A Look into the Future of Design</title>
    <link href="/posts/design-trends-2023-a-look-into-the-future-of-design/"/>
    <updated>2023-04-17T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>/posts/design-trends-2023-a-look-into-the-future-of-design/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Design, like many other professions, is a constantly evolving field, and staying current with the latest trends and techniques is essential for any designer. As we are already nearing the first quarter of 2023, there have been many exciting changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;In this article, we will explore the emerging design trends that will shape the field throughout 2023 and the coming years.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From minimalist aesthetics to exciting new color palettes, we have a lot to look forward to!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Minimalism Reimagined&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It feels as though Minimalism has been a popular design trend for years, and it shows no signs of slowing down. However, as we continue to push the boundaries of style in 2023 we can expect to see bold new takes on this classic style. Rather than just stripping designs down to their bare essentials, designers will start to explore more innovative minimalist aesthetics. This had already begun to include the use of negative space in creative ways, or the incorporation of subtle geometric patterns. An extention of this is the rise of Neomorphism, a visual effect that utilises background colours, shadows, shapes, gradients, and highlights to achieve defined, yet minimal, graphic effects for user interface components.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Bold Color Palettes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In recent years, muted tones and pastels have dominated the world of design. However, in 2023 we can expect to see a shift towards bolder, more vibrant color palettes. This trend is driven in part by the rise of mobile design, where striking colors are needed to grab user attention. Expect to see bright, eye-catching hues paired with unexpected combinations of complementary colors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These colors will help to inject playfulness and fun with their vibrant and highly-saturated hues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;case-img &quot; src=&quot;/static/images/blog/design-trends-2023-a-look-into-the-future-of-design/color.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bold color&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Bold color is coming: Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@jannerboy62?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Nick Fewings&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/photos/1zJkgcOS0is?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Next-Level 3D Graphics&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technological advancements and AI-based content generators have made it easy to create and source much more sophisticated 3D graphics, and designers are eager to take advantage of this. In 2023, we can expect to see more intricate and detailed 3D models, in both web and product design. This will create a more immersive experience for users, and allow designers to push the envelope even further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;case-img &quot; src=&quot;/static/images/blog/design-trends-2023-a-look-into-the-future-of-design/hand.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;3D hand graphic&quot; style=&quot;height: auto;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;3D Graphics: Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@rizki1123?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Muhammad Rizki&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/photos/5tZRN6LZ2Tw?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Natural Elements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amidst a world dominated by technology, there is a growing desire for designs that feel more organic and natural. This trend will continue to gain momentum in 2023, with designers incorporating more natural elements into their work. Expect to see an emphasis on organic shapes and textures, as well as the use of natural colors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are seeing some of this with the calm and cool color palettes that many major brands, like Burger King, are adopting as they continue to push on in the wave of retro nostalgia rebranding. In doing so they are hoping to draw us to the percieved safety of brands that remind us of a much less technologically dominated time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;case-img &quot; src=&quot;/static/images/blog/design-trends-2023-a-look-into-the-future-of-design/bk.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Retro Burger King logo&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Retro Burger King redesign: Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@rizki1123?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Muhammad Rizki&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/photos/5tZRN6LZ2Tw?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Design is an ever-changing field, and keeping up with the latest trends is essential. As we approach 2023, we can expect to see exciting changes in the world of design. From innovative minimalist aesthetics to bold colors and intricate 3D graphics, the future looks bright for designers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incorporating these trends into your own work will help you stay ahead of the curve, and create designs that are both visually stunning and user-friendly. So, what are you waiting for? Get out there and start experimenting with these exciting new trends!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Best Tools for Building a Design System</title>
    <link href="/posts/best-tools-for-building-a-design-system/"/>
    <updated>2023-04-16T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>/posts/best-tools-for-building-a-design-system/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Design systems have become an integral part of the design process. They provide consistency, efficiency, and scalability to design teams. However, creating design systems from scratch can be a tedious and overwhelming process. This is where design system tools come in handy. In this article, we will explore the best design system tools currently available in the market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Design System Tools: Streamlining Your Design Process&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Design system tools are software applications that help in the creation, management, and implementation of design systems. These tools enable designers to create UI components, style guides, documentation, and more. Let&#39;s dive into some of the best design system tools:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Figma&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;case-img&quot; src=&quot;/static/images/blog/best-tools-for-building-a-design-system/figma.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;figma website on laptop&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Photo by &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/@tracycodes?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Tracy Adams&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/photos/rA5MU4pXnWE?utm_source=unsplash&amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.figma.com/&quot;&gt;Figma&lt;/a&gt; is a cloud-based design tool that allows teams to collaborate on design projects in real-time. One of the standout features of Figma is its ability to create design systems as well as prototype. With no coding knowledge required, designers can create and maintain design systems efficiently. Figma&#39;s collaborative features also make it easier to share and iterate on design components.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Sketch&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sketch.com/&quot;&gt;Sketch&lt;/a&gt; is a design tool that has gained popularity among designers due to its focus on interface design. Sketch&#39;s design system tool, Craft Library, allows designers to create and manage design systems within Sketch. The tool also enables designers to reuse design components across multiple projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;InVision Design System Manager (DSM)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://support.invisionapp.com/docs/what-is-dsm&quot;&gt;InVision DSM&lt;/a&gt; is a design system tool that provides a centralized hub for design systems. The tool allows designers to create, manage, and share design systems with their teams. DSM also provides version control, making it easier to keep track of updates and changes to the design system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Lingo&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lingoapp.com/&quot;&gt;Lingo&lt;/a&gt; is a design system tool that helps teams collaborate on design systems. With Lingo, designers can easily organize, share, and reuse design assets. Lingo also provides a style guide feature that enables designers to document their design system components.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Storybook&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike the other design systems mentioned &lt;a href=&quot;https://storybook.js.org/&quot;&gt;Storybook&lt;/a&gt; is a system that can be used directly in your project. While it does require a bit of coding knowledge, the automatically generated docs and long list of tutorials will help guide you to getting set up easily. This is a strong recommendation for designers who are familiar with creating components in HTML, CSS and Js.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Design system tools are a must-have for design teams looking to streamline their design process. These tools enable designers to create and manage design components efficiently, resulting in more cohesive and consistent designs. Figma, Sketch, InVision DSM, Lingo and Storybook are some of the best design system tools available in the market at the time of writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re a design team looking to streamline your design process, consider using one of the design system tools mentioned above. With these tools, you can create better, more cohesive designs, much faster and more efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Designing Ethical Products</title>
    <link href="/posts/designing-ethical-products/"/>
    <updated>2022-11-09T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>/posts/designing-ethical-products/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Design has become addictive&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a digital designer, the things you work on can have a serious impact on those around you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since its beginnings there has always been individuals who have warned against the addictiveness of computer use. Jumping forward to today, dark patterns, used to manipulate how individuals act online is more rampant than ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is defined as Internet Addiction Disorder &lt;em&gt;(IAD)&lt;/em&gt; and classed as a form of behavioural addiction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Ethical design&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ethical design refers to design that resists manipulative patterns, respects data privacy, encourages co-design, and is accessible and human-centered. Currently, no universally sanctioned framework exists, though there are individual frameworks to handle some of the key aspects:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Usability&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, usability has established is a fundamental need for every digital interface. If a product is not intuitive to use, it is viewed as a design failure and users will leave in droves. And rightly so; with things like cars having digital user interfaces it is our moral responsibility as designers to make things that are simple to use, secure, and devoid of mistakes that could cause accidents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good places to get started when creating usable interfaces is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://m2.material.io/design/environment/surfaces.html&quot;&gt;Material Design System by Google&lt;/a&gt;. Material is a design system created by Google to help teams build high-quality digital experiences for Android, iOS, Flutter, and the web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Accessibility&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like usability, inclusive design has become a standard item in the requirement list of many designers and companies. Accessible design benefits all, as it attempts to cover as many needs and capabilities as possible. The definitive source for all things accessibility are the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3.org/WAI/standards-guidelines/wcag/&quot;&gt;WCAG Guidelines&lt;/a&gt;. These are an internationally recognised set of recommendations for improving web accessibility. If you find these guidelines a bit daunting then a few other great resources are &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/andrewhick/accessibility/wiki&quot;&gt;Accessibility resources by Andrew Hick&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/alphagov/wcag-primer/wiki&quot;&gt;the Gov wiki for Accessibility testing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Privacy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The topic of privacy has become much more prevalent in recent years. More and more services are using privacy as their USP &lt;em&gt;(unique selling point)&lt;/em&gt;. With analytics and trackers corporations have access to an abundance of personal information. As designers we have to consider what information is strictly necessary for services to work. If sensitive information is needed, think how to be as transparent about how this will be used; make people aware of the potential risks without overloading them. There re no frameworks that I am aware of for general privacy. However, when conducting deign research &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ideo.com/post/the-little-book-of-design-research-ethics&quot;&gt;The Little Book of Design Research Ethics&lt;/a&gt; is a great place to start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Dark UX&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I often find myself on my laptop scrolling through recommended feeds on social media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Social media apps are designed to be addictive. Utilizing genuine Psychology, they are designed to keep our eyes on our screens because the more time and attention we give to these platforms, the more profit the companies generate through advertising. So, designers intentionally create features to be addictive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dark UX patterns can also be used to manipulate user journeys, forcing you onto pages or into subscriptions you didn&#39;t originally want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a responsibly for designers to lower the addictiveness of these products. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.humanetech.com/&quot;&gt;The Center for Humane Technology&lt;/a&gt; has some useful information on this topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;It is tough to create a business case for ethics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ideally, in design projects, we should always map out exactly how we can prevent creating addictive and inaccessible products. However, the reality is much less simple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many constraints &lt;em&gt;(time, budget, resources)&lt;/em&gt; to consider all the ethical implications of our work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In many cases, companies simply do not see the value of investing into it. As a designer you have to push against many existing internal paradigms which if not managed correctly are akin to the task faced by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sisyphus&quot;&gt;Sisyphus&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the best ways to get started are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Company Values&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If mission and values of the companies we work for align with any of these ethics, we can challenge the company to truly live up to its promises and support it in carrying out its mission. This is tough if the values do not line up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Testing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conducting regular user tests with stakeholders, and working collaboratively with different departments helps to identify the edge cases. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.uxdesigninstitute.com/blog/usability-test-how-many-users/&quot;&gt;Many forms of testing don&#39;t require a large group of participants to yield effective results&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Frameworks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some UI frameworks like the aforementioned &lt;a href=&quot;https://m2.material.io/design/environment/surfaces.html&quot;&gt;Material Design System&lt;/a&gt; can really help to handle accessible and usable components. &lt;a href=&quot;https://design-system.service.gov.uk/components/&quot;&gt;Gov.uk has some good component examples too&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are looking to create your own component library then &lt;a href=&quot;https://storybook.js.org/&quot;&gt;Storybook.js&lt;/a&gt; is a great tool. It helps build UI components and pages in isolation and has ally plugins to make sure components are accessible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Being Brave&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last option is the one im sure everyone likes the least, I know I do. If you truly care about making the internet a better place for everyone then sometimes you just have to put your foot down and call some meetings. It might not get you too far but if you gave it your all then there is nothing more you can do.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>The Self Fulfilling Prophecy of Readable Fonts</title>
    <link href="/posts/the-self-fulfilling-prophecy-of-readable-fonts/"/>
    <updated>2022-10-28T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>/posts/the-self-fulfilling-prophecy-of-readable-fonts/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Typography should be readable&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Companies are always scrambling to improve performance and optimize products. There is immense competition to make content as consumable as possible to further the ease &lt;em&gt;(addiction)&lt;/em&gt; of the services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What makes a good typeface?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fundamentally the two key aspects of a typeface are legibility and readability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Legibility&lt;/strong&gt; is the ability to distinguish on letter from another. &lt;strong&gt;Readability&lt;/strong&gt; is how easy the process of scanning the text and understanding it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How are readable fonts decided&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the 1940&#39;s, the most popular test for legibility was the Blink Test. The idea is that as blinking is used to relieve the stress on our eyes; the fewer times you blink while reading the better the typeface. This was tested under lab conditions, with light and font size regulated, and the test subject is presented with the same text in many different faces - the number of blinks was then monitored using a handheld clicker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to these results, the type that fared best were the ones that have survived for centuries, always being revived and only being slightly modified &lt;em&gt;(Bembo, Bodoni, Garamond)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the 1970&#39;s more research was done at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rca.ac.uk/&quot;&gt;The Royal College of Art&#39;s Readability and Print Research Unit&lt;/a&gt;. From this research it was found that type with strong distinctive strokes was easier to read than flattened styles; and a greater between letters allowed faster digestion of information. The research confirmed that the key areas that make a letter distinctive are the &lt;strong&gt;top half and right side&lt;/strong&gt;. The eyes use these points to try and quickly ascertain what letter will be there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other research has found people prefer bold typefaces, although legibility remains fairly constant. Serif and sans serif faces are also equally legible, so long as they aren&#39;t too heavy and thick. There are a lot of differences that serif and sans serif can make for branding but that is a discussion for another day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to find more &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/10909804-just-my-type&quot;&gt;Just my Type by Simon Garfield has some good insight into font readability&lt;/a&gt; is a great place to start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What this means&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you look at the results above, the idea that type that has been around longest is kind of amazing. With every modern convenience, we still cant beat type that was created when printing first began. This may seem like the case but the reality is far more interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have ever played a mobile game like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/logo-quiz-can-you-identify-these-brands-when-their-names-are-stripped-out-2012-7?r=US&amp;amp;IR=T&quot;&gt;logo quiz&lt;/a&gt; you will be familiar with the idea of pattern recognition. This concept is used a lot in graphic design to hide meaning in negative space. By reusing these typefaces again and again we are making it easier and easier for our brains to recognise letters and reducing the strain they cause to read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned in my other post, &lt;a href=&quot;/posts/junking-for-graphic-design-inspiration/&quot;&gt;Junking for graphic design inspiration&lt;/a&gt;, the use of old material is inspiration for a lot of modern type too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The radical Californian type designer &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zuzana_Licko&quot;&gt;Zuzana Licko&lt;/a&gt; has a popular theory that &#39;you read best what you read most&#39;. &#39;You need to use something that is not necessarily intrinsically more legible, but that people are used to seeing.&#39;When you look at some of the most legible typefaces that we have currently, it&#39;s easy to see how this could be true. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/&quot;&gt;The search engine Google&lt;/a&gt; uses Arial as it&#39;s primary font for search results. Sure enough, Arial can be found in the article &lt;a href=&quot;https://gathercontent.com/blog/what-makes-a-good-accessible-easy-to-read-font&quot;&gt;What makes a good, accessible, easy to read font?&lt;/a&gt; along with Microsofts in house typeface; Calibri. These principles also work for things like page layouts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Design as a small fish&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a small fish company this does mean that creating something new is much harder. Due to these recognition principles, unless you have some great unique selling point you may find people unwilling to learn an unfamiliar system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, mimicking larger competitors who have already &#39;optimized&#39; their websites typography and layouts gives you an excellent opportunity to create your own service with minimal onboarding; users will already be familiar with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While you can use these sites and type for inspiration, make sure you still give it your own unique style, messages and branding or people won&#39;t bother using your site at all!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Junking for graphic design inspiration</title>
    <link href="/posts/junking-for-graphic-design-inspiration/"/>
    <updated>2022-10-05T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>/posts/junking-for-graphic-design-inspiration/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;A lot of things nowadays seems to be made without any real care for craft&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While it may feel as though the era of true craftmanship is behind us, there are still plenty of ways to learn from the past. Getting into town and finding some local antique / charity shops can provide a wealth of different ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Sourcing Inspiration&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some absolutely fantastic designers who use the &amp;quot;junking&amp;quot; method of looking for inspiration. Notable ones include Aaron Draplin, the founder of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.draplin.com&quot;&gt;Draplin Design Company&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/&quot;&gt;Hoefler&amp;amp;Co&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These successful and influential people pour through retro and historic pieces for interesting graphics and typographic inspiration. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.toptal.com/designers/ui/typeface-history&quot;&gt;In fact, the first typeface, used by Johannes Gutenberg on the first printing press, was created to mimic the calligraphic handwriting used by monks to hand-transcribe manuscripts&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What to look for&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best things to look for if you are starting out are books, signs and branded items that are retro and really show attention to detail. Getting your hands on slightly more expensive or hand crafted items &lt;em&gt;(or just taking some pictures of it)&lt;/em&gt; can also be great. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.typography.com/blog/introducing-decimal&quot;&gt;The font &amp;quot;Decimal&amp;quot; was inspired by vintage watch lettering&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On my travels, I am always intrigued by the different typography and graphics. It&#39;s interesting to see how cities adopt fonts and how different styles can be traced back to much more humble beginnings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;case-img &quot; src=&quot;/static/images/blog/junking-for-graphic-design-inspiration/typography.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hand painted sign from a historic Welsh village&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Hand painted sign from a historic Welsh village&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Go outside&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that you know where to go all I can say is go and get stuck in. Once you start keeping an eye out you will be astounded at what you can find.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Choosing A Modern Color Palette For Your Brand</title>
    <link href="/posts/choosing-a-modern-color-palette-for-your-brand/"/>
    <updated>2022-08-22T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>/posts/choosing-a-modern-color-palette-for-your-brand/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Why is your brand color palette so important?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether you&#39;ve decided to start a new side hustle, or are launching a game-changing startup, understanding color theory and its effects on consumer behavior will help you communicate your brand values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;It helps people understand who you are and why you’re here – which, in turn, attracts the right customers to your brand.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, I&#39;m going to help steer you to choose the right colors for your brand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Start with some inspiration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start by creating a mood board of any colors and images you feel align closely with your brand identity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find inspiration anywhere. Follow artists on Instagram, &lt;a href=&quot;https://dribbble.com/&quot;&gt;dribbble&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.behance.net/&quot;&gt;behance&lt;/a&gt; or use &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pinterest.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Pinterest&lt;/a&gt; to create dedicated boards by color.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While researching for this post I also found &lt;a href=&quot;https://copy-paste-css.com/color-palettes&quot;&gt;a tool to showcase color palettes from different brands&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Consider color psychology&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Color psychology is the study of how colors affect perceptions and behaviors. It allows us to understand color and use it to our advantage, especially when it comes to branding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of research has gone into color theory. You can definitely get lost down the rabbit hole finding the story behind each color. Below is a quick summary to give you an idea. If you want to learn more I would recommend books like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/59513231-the-colour-code&quot;&gt;The Colour Code: Why we see red, feel blue and go green&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style=&quot;color:red&quot;&gt;Red&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Danger, excitement, love, passion and energy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style=&quot;color:pink&quot;&gt;Pink&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sentimental and romantic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style=&quot;color:orange;&quot;&gt;Orange&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fresh, creative, fun and adventurous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style=&quot;color:yellow;&quot;&gt;Yellow&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Optimistic, playful and happy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style=&quot;color:green;&quot;&gt;Green&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Natural. It is most often used to depict the environment sustainability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style=&quot;color:red;&quot;&gt;Red&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trustworthy, reliable and calming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style=&quot;color:purple;&quot;&gt;Purple&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Royalty and opulence. It can be connected to spiritualism and mystery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style=&quot;color:brown;&quot;&gt;Brown&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honest, organic and wholesome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style=&quot;color: white; text-shadow: -1px -1px 0 #000, 1px -1px 0 #000, -1px 1px 0 #000, 1px 1px 0 #000;&quot;&gt;White&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pure. It conveys simplicity and innocence, often with a minimalistic feel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style=&quot;color:black&quot;&gt;Black&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sophisticated and elegant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 style=&quot;background: red; background: -webkit-linear-gradient(left, orange , yellow, green, cyan, blue, violet); background: -o-linear-gradient(right, orange, yellow, green, cyan, blue, violet); background: -moz-linear-gradient(right, orange, yellow, green, cyan, blue, violet); background: linear-gradient(to right, orange , yellow, green, cyan, blue, violet); -webkit-background-clip: text; -webkit-text-fill-color: transparent;&quot;&gt;Muticolored&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;United or open to anything. It’s great for capturing the spirit of diversity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Different hues and shades of colors also contribute to the color story. Brighter shades can be seen as much more youthful, modern and bold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;You don&#39;t always have to be like the competition!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An interesting detail in the book &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/en/book/show/34964879-how-to-turn-down-a-billion-dollars&quot;&gt;How to Turn Down a Billion Dollars: The Snapchat Story&lt;/a&gt; is that the logo for Snapchat was chosen by looking at the top 100 apps in the app store and discovering none were yellow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;While its great to try and emulate some of the brand leaders, its even better to forge your own path.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is especially good if you are, or are looking to, &lt;a href=&quot;https://econsultancy.com/what-is-a-challenger-brand-definition/&quot;&gt;become a challenger brand&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Palette Generators&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you have your main colors chosen I would recommend using online tools to build up your palette quickly and easily. &lt;a href=&quot;https://color.adobe.com/&quot;&gt;Adobe color wheel&lt;/a&gt; is a great way to understand and choose complementary colors. Once you&#39;ve generated a color palette it can even be saved into &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.adobe.com/uk/creativecloud.html&quot;&gt;Creative Cloud&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://coolors.co/&quot;&gt;Coolors&lt;/a&gt; is another top pick. It is a super fast palette generator. There are also many color schemes created by many of its 3 million users to browse and get inspired by. This site has been expanded to allow plugins to a lot of applications too making it easier to get started using your new palette.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It is very easy to get lost when looking at color palettes. When defining a palette a good rule of thumb is to stick with 1 or 2 primary colors and around 3 secondary colors.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So there you have it, a fairly concise guide to choosing the right colors for your brand &lt;em&gt;(I will be creating more content for game design palettes in the future)&lt;/em&gt;. I hope it helped and I look forward to seeing your brands shining out there in the world!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Learning new skills for free</title>
    <link href="/posts/learning-new-skills-for-free/"/>
    <updated>2022-08-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>/posts/learning-new-skills-for-free/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;What skills do you want to learn?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The best thing to do before signing up to anything is deciding what you want to learn. Many platforms, no matter what they claim all have specialisms or courses that really stand out in different fields.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, I wanted to get some experience with Unity 2D and C#. After a few weeks of experimenting here are my top picks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Sololearn &lt;em&gt;(C#)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sololearn.com&quot;&gt;Sololearn has the world&#39;s largest collection of FREE programming courses&lt;/a&gt;. Options including: Python, C++, JavaScript, Java, jQuery, machine learning, data science. As a bonus you receive a certificate for each course you complete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While a bit frustrating to progress in a language you already know, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sololearn.com&quot;&gt;SoloLearn can be an awesome learning tool for the fundamentals&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Positives&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good community&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integrated IDE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A lot of content covered&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FREE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Certification&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Negatives&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hard if you&#39;ve never coded before&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ads! Ads! Ads!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Youtube &lt;em&gt;(Unity)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#&quot;&gt;YouTube is a free video sharing website&lt;/a&gt; where users can watch, like, share, comment and upload their own videos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With &lt;strong&gt;500 Hours of Video Uploaded to YouTube Every Minute&lt;/strong&gt;, if you do a little digging, there are a ton of great tutorials!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Positives&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good community&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integrated IDE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A lot of content covered&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FREE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Negatives&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Limited amount of content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not always a lot of helpful comments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ads! Ads! Ads!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No certification&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Skillshare &lt;em&gt;(Unity)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.skillshare.com&quot;&gt;Skillshare is an online learning community with loads of classes&lt;/a&gt;. There are courses for illustration, design, photography, video, freelancing, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know you are probably thinking that Skillshare
is a paid platform... and you would be right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, if you are looking to learn some very specific content in a short time frame you can get up to 2 months for free by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Y3Zd00Wz8Bc&quot;&gt;extending Skillshare free trial (No creditcard needed)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Positives&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Large selection of courses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Free one month trial&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Refer a friend = 1 month additional free&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Live sessions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Negatives&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not free forever&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quality of courses vary&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No certification&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Library&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final option in the list is a lot more low-tec, but no less effective! Signing up to your local library is a really good way to get access to a ton of free resources and provides a great place to study alone or with others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Positives&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Large selection of resources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Free&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Great place to study&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meet and support community&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Negatives&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure to return nooks on time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quality of material varies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No certification&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No matter where you choose to learn, there are plenty of options that won&#39;t break the bank. Get out there and kick ass. &lt;strong&gt;I BELIEVE IN YOU!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Creating an Indie Brand Logo</title>
    <link href="/posts/creating-an-indie-brand-logo/"/>
    <updated>2022-07-25T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>/posts/creating-an-indie-brand-logo/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Why Make A Logo?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;When you are considering all of the factors that go into building a business, creating a logo might not seem like a top priority.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be honest with you, its not the most important thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you read books like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.waterstones.com/book/the-lean-startup/eric-ries/9780670921607%22&quot;&gt;The lean startup&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.waterstones.com/book/start-it-up/luke-johnson/9780670920471&quot;&gt;Start it up&lt;/a&gt; they defintely don&#39;t spend the whole time talking about spending hours making a pixel perfect logo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The perfect logo is not everyones first port of call. That being said, here are the main reasons I chose to start here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;1. It Grabs ATTENTION&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attention spans are short these days &lt;em&gt;(especially consumers)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good logo is the split second opportunity to grab someones attention and communicate your brand. Having a stand out logo among all the others is a solid method of getting someone to give you a chance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;2. It&#39;s a great way to start thinking about your brand&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When creating a logo, it obviously has to fit your values, your market and stand out against your competition. Creating a logo is a great way to get the cogs turning and allows you to think in more detail about what you want to build.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;3. It&#39;s Fun&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m probably biased because of my interest in all things art and design; but flexing those creative muscles is definitely something I love doing. If I had all the time in the world I could easily spend it coming up with new ideas!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Alright I&#39;m convinced! How do I start?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m hoping by this point you have been convinced, here are the steps to making a logo for yourself:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;What are people doing in this space?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best products are a combination of familiarity and novelty, you don&#39;t need to start from scratch and you don&#39;t need to reinvent the wheel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have a look around at some of the brand leaders, legacy brands or challengers in the space you want to enter. What do you like about them? Some real inspirations I found for game development are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.teamcherry.com.au&quot;&gt;Team cherry&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://studiomdhr.com&quot;&gt;Studio MDHR&lt;/a&gt;. Their game styles and company values are things that I really felt a connection with during my search.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Where can I get my creative juices flowing?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to see how creative professionals create innovative logos, check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://dribbble.com/&quot;&gt;Dribbble&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.awwwards.com/&quot;&gt;Awwwards&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.behance.net/&quot;&gt;Behance&lt;/a&gt;. If you find those intimidating or pretentious then &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com&quot;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt; works too. You&#39;d be surprised where else you draw inspiration from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some places to look for images are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pinterest.com/&quot;&gt;Pinterest&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you&#39;ve got all your inspiration lay it out into a moodboard and you are ready for the next step...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;2. Ideation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time to put pen to paper and sketch out some designs. Choose the medium you are the most comfortable with and get started. You could use pen and paper, Procreate or another tablet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A method I sometimes use for sketching rapidly and coming up with ideas is &lt;a href=&quot;https://designsprintkit.withgoogle.com/methodology/phase3-sketch/crazy-8s&quot;&gt;Crazy 8&#39;s&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;case-img &quot; src=&quot;/static/images/blog/creating-a-brand-logo/ideation.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;sketching some ideas for the FoxGibbon logo&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Some early logo sketches&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;3.Refine&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you have a solid concept its time to get that bad boy into Adobe Illustrator!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I have a design I like I usually photograph or scan the sketch and use the pen tool to make the graphic. &lt;em&gt;(A good tip for logo design is to always work in black and white so you aren&#39;t distracted or influenced by colour, flipping the image can also help identify where needs to be balanced.)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;4.Revel&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give one glance, to make sure it&#39;s really happening. This is your moment. Soak it in, you&#39;ve earned one glance. F*** it! Fully behold your creation. You&#39;ve earned this. Months of planning. It&#39;s all happening. Feel the warmth. Tweet the picture, you&#39;ve earned one tweet. Tweet a picture of you next to the logo. Defiant and proud. This is your moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;case-img &quot; src=&quot;/static/images/blog/creating-a-brand-logo/logo-bw.png&quot; alt=&quot;FoxGibbon logo&quot; style=&quot;height: auto;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;A final look at the FoxGibbon logo&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>First Post</title>
    <link href="/posts/first-post/"/>
    <updated>2022-06-09T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>/posts/first-post/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;First Post&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Welcome to Fox Gibbon.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fox Gibbon is place for tech, design and hobby enthusiasts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have created this website as a place to find up to date tutorials, news and discussions. The aim is truly to try and pull back the design and technology a little further for people who are new to design, professionals or just generally interested. I&#39;m aiming to place a strong emphasis on good practice, accessibility and want to make these posts as easy to digest as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One day I would also like to make this a place to celebrate brands that are independent, challenging the big brands with amazing new innovations. But for now I am just one man and a laptop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sounds Cool?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you like the sound of this then why not bookmark this website or follow me on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/FoxGibbon%22&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; to keep up with all the action. Aiming to create a new posts every 2 weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you read this far then thankyou for reading. Why not see some of the &lt;a href=&quot;/&quot;&gt;Latest Posts&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to contribute a post, I will be adding a readme with more information on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ThomasMott/fg&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; soon. Everything is open source, feel free to add anything you think would be interesting :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;It is never too late to be what you might have been.&amp;quot; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;span&gt;~ George Elliot&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;case-img&quot; src=&quot;/static/images/blog/first-post/rock.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The rock face meme&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;It&#39;s about drive, it&#39;s about power.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
